danielmainawaweru@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio |

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with 2 years of proven experience improving legacy code, and building solutions. I specialize in React, Ruby on Rails, and Postgres. Excellent learner, excited about leveraging advances in software development towards crafting tools for intuitive problem-solving.

## SKILLS

Front-End: React, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Django

**Tools & Methods:** Git, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools **Professional:** Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Asynchronous work, Communication,

Languages: English-Professional, Swahili-Native

## EXPERIENCE

Minaw Ventures Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

Jan 2020 - Sep 2020

- Successfully initialized, designed, and deployed more than 15 web applications.
- Pitched more than 10 projects to clients with a high degree of customer support, strategizing and ensuring on-time delivery, compliance, and quality assurance.
- Slashed payroll/benefits administration costs by 20% by negotiating pricing and fees while
  ensuring the continuation of services and product enhancements.
- Led a team of 10 remote-first developers in designing and developing a booking system using React for the user interface to ensure faster response and load times.
- Learned a new language (Ruby) and its framework (Rails) in 3 months and managed to do 4 projects, including creating a restful API.

## **Nakuru County Government**

Nakuru, Kenya

IT intern

Sep 2019 - Dec 2019

- After only a few weeks on the job, I was promoted to Unit lead Managed, trained, and onboarded 10+ IT interns to troubleshoot and solve computer errors effectively.
- Successfully ran a server, ensuring smooth operation of the ICT center.
- Utilized network operations best practices to troubleshoot connectivity issues, and increase
  the internet speed by 30%. This improvement led to a company-wide increase in efficiency
  and output.
- Successfully operated and trained more than 1000 farmers on Farmers Care ATM, an ICT booth with information on modern farming practices.

## **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE Mar 2021- Nov 2021

## Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, Test Driven Development, and daily stand-ups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology Diploma, Information Technology

May 2018 - Dec 2019

- Mastered programming basics, computer software applications, and hardware functionalities.
- Learned system administration and networking.

## HIGHLIGHTED FREELANCE PROJECTS

<u>Vacation Booking App</u>— an online booking app that allows users to see destinations, reserve a destination, and view all their reservations. Repository on Github.

• Built with: (React, React, Bootstrap)

<u>Micro Reddit</u> —This project replicates how Reddit apps function. It tests the MVC structure implementation in Rails. Repository on Github

• Built with: (Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap)